Rebekah Crawford and Linda Clarke-Smith Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Rebekah Crawford and Linda Clarke-Smith Papers 1715-1929 (bulk 1890-1929)
MSS17186
Crawford, Rebekah, 1845-1934
Clarke-Smith, Linda
3,500 items
11 containers plus 3 oversize
4.4 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Educator and social worker. Correspondence, scrapbooks, and miscellaneous papers concerning relief work with the Red Cross and Duryea War Relief during and after World War I with Italian and French war wounded and children. Also includes family papers, account books, scrapbooks, manuscript plays and miscellany, some relating to Richard Crawford.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Clarke-Smith, Linda. Rebekah Crawford and Linda Clarke-Smith papers. 1715-1929.; Crawford family.; Crawford, Rebekah, 1845-1934.; Crawford, Richard, 1738-1798. Richard Crawford account and ledger books. 1753-1830.
Organizations
American Red Cross.; Duryea War Relief.
Subjects
World War, 1914-1918--War work--France.; World War, 1914-1918--War work--Italy.
Occupations
Archaeologists.; Educators.; Nurses.; Social workers.
Provenance
The papers of Rebekah Crawford, educator and social worker, and Linda Clarke-Smith, archaeologist and volunteer nurse, were given to the Library of Congress by Crawford in 1928-1929 and by her estate in 1934. Although the majority of the papers belonged to Rebekah Crawford, she asked that the collection be referred to as the "Rebekah Crawford and Linda Clarke-Smith Collection" to honor the relief work of Linda Clarke-Smith, her niece.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Rebekah Crawford and Linda Clarke-Smith are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Rebekah Crawford
Date Event
1846 Born, Brooklyn, N.Y.
1869 1910 Music teacher, Crawford Private School, Brooklyn, N.Y.
1890 1924 Wrote four books on music appreciation for children
1910 Head of Music Department, Crawford Private School, Brooklyn, N.Y.
1913 1920 Relief worker, including during World War I
1916 1918 Raised funds for artificial limbs for 150 indigent Italian soldiers
1920 Received Gold Medal from Italian Red Cross for Italian relief efforts
1921 Received Distinguished Service Medal of the Order of the Crown of Italy for Italian and Duryea relief work
1934, Jan. 25 Died, New York, N.Y.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Rebekah Crawford (1845-1934) and Linda Clarke-Smith span the years 1715-1929, with the bulk of the material dating from 1890 to 1929. The papers are organized into the following series: Scrapbooks, Family Papers, and Miscellany. Although the majority of the papers belonged to Rebekah Crawford, she asked that the collection be referred to as the "Rebekah Crawford and Linda Clarke-Smith Collection" to honor the relief work of Linda Clarke-Smith, her niece.
The Scrapbooks document Crawford's relief work during and after World War I in Italy and France with the Duryea Relief Agency and the American Red Cross. The series also includes collected material concerning Edgar Allan Poe, Emma Trapper, Mary Alethea and the Spanish-American War.
The Family Papers contain correspondence, genealogical material, Crawford family documents, ancestral tablets, printed articles, an essay on Crawford genealogy, scrapbooks, indentures of transfers of land, account and ledger books of Richard Crawford, wills, drafts of wills, unidentifiable financial records, and miscellaneous pieces of old documents.and writings.
The Miscellany series includes photographs, postcards, and printed matter.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged in four series:
Scrapbooks, 1898-1928
Family Papers, 1715-1929
Miscellany, circa 1900-1928
Oversize, 1900-1922
Container List
- Scrapbooks, 1898-1928 (Box 1-8)
  Scrapbooks including correspondence, photographs, financial records, postcards, printed material, and memorabilia.
  Organized by subject matter.
  - Italian Relief (Box 1)
    - 1913-1924, (2 volumes) (Box 1)
    - 1918-1921, (2 volumes) (Box 2)
    - 1917-1921, (4 volumes) (Box 3)
  - Duryea relief, 1914-1921, (3 volumes) (Box 4)
  - Red Cross work, 1917-1921, (2 volumes) (Box 5)
  - Other war work, 1817-1920 See also Oversize, (3 volumes) (Box 5)
  - Emma Trapper, 1894-1896 (Box 6)
  - Spanish-American War, 1898-1899 (Box 7)
  - Edgar Allan Poe, 1915-1928, (1 volume) (Box 7)
  - Edgar Allan Poe, 1915-1928, (1 volume) (Box 8)
  - Letters of Mary Alethea Woodward, circa 1926-1928, (2 volumes) (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1900-1928 See also Oversize, (3 volumes) (Box 8)
- Family Papers, 1715-1929 (Box 9-11)
  Correspondence, writings, genealogical material, indentures of transfers of land, account and ledger books of Richard Crawford, and miscellaneous documents including wills, financial records, and other family documents.
  Arranged by type of material and chronologically therein.
  - Genealogical material (Box 9)
    - Ancestral tablets, circa 1898 (Box 9)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box 9)
    - Printed articles, 1914-1918 (Box 9)
    - Scrapbook, 1781-1921 (Box 9)
  - Crawford historic documents (Box 9)
    - Indentures of transfer of land, 1715-1844 (Box 9)
    - Account and ledger books of Richard Crawford, 1753-1830, (1 folder) (Box 9)
    - Account and ledger books of Richard Crawford, 1753-1830, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Report of fortifications, Gibraltar, 1768 (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1730-1866 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, incoming, 1884-1929, undated (Box 10)
  - Collection of essays, lectures, plays and poems (Box 10)
    - Essays (Box 10)
      - Buchelew, John D., miscellaneous philosophical essays, 1848-1849 (Box 10)
      - Clarke-Smith, Linda, "A Revival of an Ancient Ritual at Siena" (Box 10)
      - Crawford-Cox, Alethea B., "Edgar Allan Poe" (Box 10)
      - Crawford-Cox, Alethea B., and Alice Chapin, essays on various literary figures (Box 10)
      - Wilson, W. Kuncbel, "The French Revolution and Napoleon Bonaparte" (Box 10)
      - Unknown authors, miscellaneous topics (Box 10)
    - Speeches (Box 10)
      - Blagrove, Alexander, untitled speech, 1910 (Box 10)
      - Briche, John S., untitled speech given at the Freehold Institute, 1849 (Box 10)
    - Poems, 1795-1917 (Box 11)
    - Plays (Box 11)
      - Cabac, "The Misanthropical Mister," parts 1-4, (3 folders) (Box 11)
      - Authors unknown (Box 11)
        - "A Day of Unforgiveness" (Box 11)
        - "If They Were Women" (Box 11)
        - "The Indian" (Box 11)
        - Untitled (Box 11)
- Miscellany, circa 1900-1928 (Box 11)
  Magazine clippings, notes, photographs, postcards, and printed material.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Magazines (Box 11)
    - Poetry Review, vol. 19, May-June, 1928 (Box 11)
    - La France, vol. IV, no. 7, Apr. 1920 (Box 11)
  - Notes, circa 1900-1927, undated (Box 11)
  - Photographs, 1900-1920 (Box 11)
  - Postcards, undated (Box 11)
  - Printed miscellany, circa 1917-1926 (Box 11)
  - Awards, 1920-1922 See Oversize (Box 11)
- Oversize, 1900-1922 (Box OV 1-OV 3)
  Scrapbooks and awards.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Scrapbooks (Box OV 1)
    - Other war work, "Colonie dei Giovani Lavoratori," agricultural colony for war-orphan boys, 1919 (Container 5) (Box OV 1)
    - Miscellaneous, postcard collection, circa 1900-1904 (Container 8) (Box OV 2)
  - Miscellany (Box OV 3)
    - Awards, 1920-1922 (Container 11) (Box OV 3)